Guide to the Anaconda Copper Mining Company records 1876-1974
Montana Historical Society
- Standard Fire Brick Company / Brick Department
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Business statements, 1901-1918, 1925-1933 (Volume 1117- 1118)
    - Cash book, 1895-1903 (Volume 1119)
    - Cost sheets and business statements (annual), 1923-1956 (Volume 1120- 1122)
    - "Departmental journal", 1895-1899 (Volume 1123)
    - Inventories, 1895-1897, 1903, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 471 / 5-6)
    - Journal, July-October 1895 (Volume 1124)
    - Ledgers, 1895-1898, 1905, 1916-1919 (Volume 1125- 1127)
    - "Payrolls and trial balances", 1897-1907 (Volume 1128)
    - "Reports of operations and cost", 1895-1898 (Box-folder 471 / 7-10)
    - "Reports of operations and cost", 1899-1904 (Box-folder 472 / 1-6)
    - "Reports on distribution, etc.", 1890 (Box-folder 473 / 1)
    - Transcript of books, 1911-1920 (Box-folder 473 / 2-11)
    - Transcript of books, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 474 / 1)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 474 / 2)
  - Legal Documents
    - Quit claim deed: City of Anaconda, 1891 (Box-folder 474 / 3)
  - Organizational Records
    - Record book (includes stock subscription, minutes, bylaws), 1890-1891 (Box-folder 474 / 4)
    - Stock book, 1891 (Box-folder 474 / 5)
    - "Stockholders' admission of service", 1891 (Box-folder 474 / 6)
- Standard Publishing Company
  - Financial Records
    - Balance sheets (re old account), 1894-1895 (Box-folder 474 / 7)
    - Balance sheets (re new account), 1895-1896 (Box-folder 474 / 8)
    - Business statements, 1928-1949 (Volume 1129- 1130)
    - Transcript of books, 1936-1943 (Volume 1131)
- Statistical Department
  - Clippings
    - Scrapbook of clippings on ACM and its employees, 1947-1959 (Volume 1132)
- Summit Wood Company
  - Financial Records
    - Journal, 1895-1900 (Box-folder 474 / 9)
- Thompson Falls Land and Lumber Company
  - Financial Records
    - Basin Agency journal, 1895-1896 (Box-folder 474 / 10)
    - Cash book, 1894-1898 (Volume 1133)
    - Journal, 1894-1898 (Volume 1134)
    - Ledger and index, 1895-1898 (Volume 1135- 1136)
    - Sales book, 1894-1896 (Volume 1137)
    - Miscellaneous (includes material on predecessor company Lavell Brothers), 1892-1896 (Box-folder 474 / 11)
- Timber Butte Milling Company
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Accounts receivable, 1926-1928 (Volume 1138)
    - Assay reports, 1928 (Box-folder 475 / 1a)
    - Cash books, 1914-1928 (Volume 1139- 1144)
    - Concentrate shipments and returns, 1922-1927 (Volume 1145)
    - General ledgers, 1914-1928 (Volume 1146- 1148)
    - Journals, 1914-1928 (Volume 1149- 1153)
    - Ledger, 1912-1927 (Box-folder 475 / 1)
    - Ore settlements: Crystal Copper Company, 1925-1930 (Box-folder 475 / 2)
    - Ore settlements: Elm Orlu, Alice, Otisco, Evaline, Poser, Queen, Galt, Silver Prince mines, 1927 (Box-folder 475 / 3)
    - Payroll, 1919-1921, 1926-1928 (Volume 1154)
    - Voucher register, 1912-1914 (Box-folder 475 / 4)
- Timber Framing and Wood Preserving Plant (Rocker)
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Cost sheets, 1948-1951 (Volume 1155)
    - Operating reports (six-month reports), 1910-1915 (Box-folder 475 / 5)
    - Time books (re payroll), January-February 1920 (Box-folder 475 / 6)
    - Time books (re payroll), 1920 March- 1921 October (Box-folder 476 / 1-5)
    - Time books (re payroll), 1921 November- 1923 July (Box-folder 477 / 1-6)
    - Time books (re payroll), 1923 August- 1924 April (Box-folder 478 / 1-3)
    - Miscellaneous (includes reports of material manufactured and horsepower used), 1903-1904 (Box-folder 478 / 4)
  - Miscellany
    - "Sketch showing requirements ACM Co. Timber Framing Plant to be located near Silver Bow or Rocker" (blueprint), 1902 (Box-folder 478 / 5)
- Tooele Valley Railway Company (Utah)
  - Financial Records
    - Cost sheets, 1909 (Volume 1156)
- Trenton Mining and Development Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book: Alex Husband, 1906-1910 (Box-folder 478 / 6)
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Cash book, 1910 (Volume 1157)
    - Cost sheets (six-month reports), 1905-1909 (Volume 1158)
    - Freight bills, 1905-1910 (Box-folder 479 / 1)
    - Gagnon Mine payroll, June 1910 (Volume 1159)
    - General journal, 1907-1910 (Volume 1160)
    - Lists of assignment of wages, 1906-1907 (Box-folder 479 / 2)
    - "Material and supplies, stock on hand, old Trenton smelter", 1895-1908 (Box-folder 479 / 3)
- Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company / Hardware and Foundry Departments
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Marcus Daly, 1894 (Box-folder 479 / 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1899-1900 (Box-folder 479 / 5)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress copies, 1890-1895 (Box-folder 479 / 6)
  - Court Papers
    - Miscellaneous (includes garnishments and letters of administration), 1942-1950 (Box-folder 479 / 7)
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Bank book and checks (re purchase of Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company by D.F. Hallahan), 1891 (Box-folder 479 / 8)
    - Business statements: all departments, 1890-1895 (Box-folder 479 / 9)
    - Anaconda hardware Department balance sheets, 1896-1901 (Box-folder 479 / 10)
    - Anaconda hardware Department cash books, 1895-1900 (Volume 1161- 1163)
    - Anaconda Hardware Department cash books, 1895-1900 (Volume 1161- 1163)
    - Anaconda Hardware Department customer ledger (includes Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1895-1896 (Volume 1164)
    - Anaconda Hardware Department day book, 1897-1899 (Box-folder 479 / 11)
    - Anaconda Hardware Department general ledger (includes Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1895-1898 (Volume 1165)
    - Anaconda Hardware Department general ledger index, 1898-1900 (Box-folder 480 / 1)
    - Anaconda Hardware Department journal (includes Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1895-1901 (Volume 1167- 1169)
    - Anaconda Hardware Department outstanding account, November 1900 (Box-folder 480 / 2)
    - Anaconda Hardware Department petty ledgers and index, 1897-1900 (Volume 1170- 1172)
    - Anaconda Hardware Department trial balances, 1898-1900 (Box-folder 480 / 3)
    - Blacksmith Shop statements, 1890-1891 (Box-folder 480 / 4)
    - Boiler Shop statements, 1890-1892 (Box-folder 480 / 5)
    - Butte Hardware Department balance sheets, 1896-1900 (Box-folder 480 / 6)
    - Butte Hardware Department business statements (re Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1890-1895 (Box-folder 480 / 7)
    - Butte Hardware Department business statements, 1900-1937 (Volume 1173)
    - Butte Hardware Department corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 480 / 8)
    - Butte Hardware Department inventory, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 480 / 9)
    - Butte Hardware Department ledger (re Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1890-1894 (Box-folder 480 / 10)
    - Butte Hardware Department ledgers (includes Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1895-1905 (Volume 1174- 1175)
    - Butte Hardware Department transcript of books, 1911-1916 (Box-folder 480 / 11-13)
    - Butte Hardware Department transcript of books, 1917-1922 (Box-folder 481 / 1-3)
    - Foundry Department account classification, 1943 (Box-folder 481 / 4)
    - Foundry Department balance sheets, etc., 1896-1902 (Box-folder 481 / 5)
    - Foundry Department bank books, cancelled checks (re Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1890-1895 (Box-folder 481 / 6)
    - Foundry Department business statements (includes Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1890-1900 (Box-folder 481 / 7-8)
    - Foundry Department business statements, 1901-1937 (Volume 1176- 1178)
    - Foundry Department corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 481 / 9)
    - Foundry Department county tax receipts, 1897-1902, 1914 (Box-folder 481 / 10)
    - Foundry Department customer ledger (includes Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1896-1900 (Volume 1179)
    - Foundry Department customer ledger index, 1896-1900 (Box-folder 481 / 11)
    - Foundry Department fire insurance, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 482 / 1)
    - Foundry Department health insurance plan, 1943-1959 (Box-folder 482 / 2)
    - Foundry Department injury case (Oscar Strom), 1897-1899 (Box-folder 482 / 3)
    - Foundry Department inventory, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 482 / 4)
    - Foundry Department ledger (re Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1891-1895 (Box-folder 482 / 5)
    - Foundry Department ledger (includes Tuttle Manufacturing and Supply Company), 1895-1905, 1940-1958 (Volume 1180- 1184)
    - Foundry Department Liberty Loan receipts, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 482 / 6)
    - Foundry Department Machinists Union subscriptions, 1944 (Box-folder 482 / 7)
    - Foundry Department personal record cards employee cards), 1920s-1940s (Box-folder 482 / 8)
    - Foundry Department statements (re brass), 1891-1892 (Box-folder 482 / 9)
    - Foundry Department statements (re iron), 1891-1892 (Box-folder 482 / 10)
    - Foundry Department supplementary detail: cost of goods sold, 1941-1946 (Box-folder 482 / 11)
    - Foundry Department supplementary detail: gross sales and earnings, 1941-1946 (Box-folder 482 / 12)
    - Foundry Department transcript of books, 1911-1916 (Box-folder 482 / 13-15)
    - Foundry Department transcript of books, 1917-1922 (Box-folder 483 / 1-3)
    - Foundry Department miscellaneous, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 483 / 4)
    - Machine Shop statements, 1890-1892 (Box-folder 483 / 5)
    - Missoula House statements, 1890 (Box-folder 483 / 6)
    - Retail Department ledger, 1891-1895 (Box-folder 483 / 7)
    - Retail Department statements, 1890-1895 (Box-folder 483 / 8)
    - Wholesale Department journal, 1891-1895 (Box-folder 483 / 9)
    - Wholesale Department ledger, 1891-1895 (Box-folder 483 / 10)
    - Wholesale Department statements, 1890-1895 (Box-folder 483 / 11)
  - Legal Documents
    - Deeds, 1890 (Box-folder 484 / 1)
    - Deeds: Moose Lake quartz mill, 1899-1903 (Box-folder 484 / 2)
    - Lease: Northern Pacific Railroad Company (re warehouse property in Missoula), 1890-1894 (Box-folder 484 / 3)
    - License agreements to manufacture, 1926-1960 (Box-folder 484 / 4)
    - Surety bond: Fred A. Baxter, 1910 (Box-folder 484 / 5)
  - Organizational Records
    - Bylaws, increase in capital stock, etc., 1891-1894 (Box-folder 484 / 6)
    - Minute book, 1890-1896 (Box-folder 484 / 7)
    - Stock certificate book, 1891-1896 (Box-folder 484 / 8)
- Victoria Mines (Elko, Nevada)
  - Financial Records
    - Cost sheets, 1945-1947 (Volume 1185)
- Washoe Copper Company
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Abstract of accounts, 1898-1905 (Box-folder 484 / 9)
    - Bill book, 1898-1904 (Volume 1186)
    - Cash books, 1894-1910 (Volume 1187- 1190)
    - Companies and individuals ledger, 1907-1910 (Volume 1191)
    - "Custom ore and matte purchased", 1907-1910 (Box-folder 484 / 10)
    - Journals, 1894-1910 (Volume 1192- 1196)
    - Land and property accounts, 1902-1904 (Box-folder 484 / 11)
    - Ledgers, 1894-1910 (Volume 1197- 1201)
    - Ore purchase advances, 1905 (Box-folder 484 / 12)
    - Ore settlements, 1905-1909 (Box-folder 484 / 13)
    - Royalties, 1904 (Box-folder 484 / 14)
    - "Statement of properties owned" [Archives Map Case], 1898 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Taxes, 1903 (Box-folder 485 / 1)
    - Voucher record books, 1898-1904 (Volume 1202- 1203)
    - Carbonado inventories, 1902, 1904 (Box-folder 485 / 2)
    - Coal Department business statements, 1907-1918 (Volume 1204)
    - Coal Department cash book, 1922-1938 (Volume 1205)
    - Coal Department corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 485 / 3)
    - Coal Department inventories, 1907-1909, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 485 / 4-5)
    - Coal Department journal, 1931-1942 (Volume 1206)
    - Coal Department ledger, 1930-1942 (Volume 1207)
    - Coal Department ledger index, 1930-1942 (Box-folder 485 / 6)
    - Coal Department shipments, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 485 / 7)
    - Coal Department shipments ("journal"), 1928-1932 (Volume 1208)
    - Coal Department transcript of books, 1911-1918 (Box-folder 485 / 8-11)
    - Coal Department transcript of books, 1919-1922 (Box-folder 486 / 1-2)
    - Coal Department voucher register, 1927-1936 (Volume 1209)
    - Coke Department business statements, 1903-1919 (Volume 1210)
    - Coke Department cash book, 1902-1905 (Box-folder 486 / 3)
    - Coke Department corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 486 / 4)
    - Coke Department general ledger balance, 1904-1905 (Box-folder 486 / 5)
    - Coke Department journals, 1902-1906 (Box-folder 486 / 6-7)
    - Coke Department ledger and index, 1902-1905 (Volume 1211- 1212)
    - Coke Department petty ledger balance, 1902-1905 (Box-folder 486 / 8)
    - Coke Department: "Statement of machinery, supplies, and material transferred from Carbon Coal Co., Carbonado, Montana...", undated (Box-folder 487 / 1)
    - Coke Department transcript of books, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 487 / 2)
    - Coke Department trial balances, 1902-1905 (Box-folder 487 / 3)
    - Coke Department voucher record/journal, 1902-1905 (Box-folder 487 / 4)
    - Mines Department cost sheets, 1905-1910 (Volume 1213)
    - Moonlight Mine time book, 1914 November (Box-folder 487 / 4a)
    - Sampling Works cost sheets, etc., 1904-1906 (Box-folder 487 / 5)
    - Sampling Works cost sheets, 1906-1930 (Volume 1214- 1217)
    - Sampling Works fire loss, July 1910 (Box-folder 487 / 6)
    - [Additional Washoe Sampling Works financial records in Ac95-2], 1905-1964 (Box-folder /)
    - Silver Lake and Cable Flats reservoirs payroll, 1898-1899 (Volume 1218)
  - Legal Documents
    - Affidavit: Snowstorm Mining Company (re sale), 1907 (Box-folder 487 / 7)
    - Agreement: U.S. Department of Agriculture (re Flint Creek Power Line), 1906 (Box-folder 487 / 8)
    - Contracts: North Butte Mining Company, Red Metal Mining Company, 1905-1907 (Box-folder 487 / 9)
    - Contracts: Helena Power Transmission Company, 1905, 1908 (Box-folder 487 / 10)
  - Reports
    - Report of Coke Department to State Coal Mine Inspector, 1906 (Box-folder 487 / 11)
  - Subject File
    - "Duval case" (re death of J.H. Duval in Mountain Con Mine; includes accident form, correspondence), 1897 August (Box-folder 487 / 12)
- West Dome Oil Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1927-1938 (Box-folder 487 / 13)
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Assets included in sale to Midwest Refining Company, 1921 December (Box-folder 487 / 14)
    - Average daily production, 1921 February-August (Box-folder 487 / 15)
    - Cash book, 1920-1936 (Box-folder 487 / 16)
    - Cost sheets and business statements, 1921 (Volume 1219)
    - Depreciation, 1921-1924 (Box-folder 487 / 17)
    - Expense distribution, 1920-1921 (Volume 1220)
    - Inventory book, 1920 (Box-folder 487 / 18)
    - Journal, 1920-1936 (Box-folder 488 / 1)
    - Ledger, 1920-1936 (Box-folder 488 / 2)
    - Montana corporate license tax, 1921-1936 (Box-folder 488 / 3)
    - Montana crude petroleum production and license tax, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 488 / 4)
    - Montana information report on income, 1933-1936 (Box-folder 488 / 5)
    - Montana net proceeds of mines tax, 1921-1936 (Box-folder 488 / 6)
    - Monthly reports to Montana Oil Conservation Board, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 488 / 7)
    - Oil production and sales, 1921-1935 (Box-folder 488 / 8)
    - Transcript of books, 1920-1930 (Box-folder 488 / 9)
    - Trial balance, 1920-1926 (Volume 1221)
    - U.S. annual information return, 1921-1936 (Box-folder 489 / 1)
    - U.S. capital stock tax, 1922-1937 (Box-folder 489 / 2)
    - U.S. corporate income and profits tax, 1920-1936 (Box-folder 489 / 3-4)
    - U.S. Geological Survey royalty statements, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 489 / 5)
    - U.S. Geological Survey /U.S. Bureau of Mines: petroleum reports, 1922-1935 (Box-folder 489 / 6)
    - U.S. oil and gas depletion schedules, 1926 (Box-folder 489 / 7)
    - U.S. producers' tax on crude petroleum, 1934 (Box-folder 489 / 8)
    - Voucher register (includes distribution of expenses), 1921-1936 (Volume 1222- 1223)
    - Miscellaneous (includes accounts payable; expenses; George M. fowler, trustee, accounts; trial balances; assets charged to surplus; development account; and royalties paid), 1920-1931 (Box-folder 489 / 9)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreements, 1920 (Box-folder 489 / 10)
  - Organizational Records
    - Annual report of corporation, 1921-1938 (Box-folder 489 / 11)
    - Oil production license, 1930 (Box-folder 489 / 12)
    - Record of stock issues and transfers, 1920-1922 (Box-folder 489 / 13)
- West Mayflower Mining Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1936 December- 1952 August (Volume 1224)
    - Journal, 1934 December- 1938 December (Box-folder 489 / 14)
    - Journal, 1939 January- 1954 September (Volume 1225)
    - Ledger ("Cedar Hollow Mining District"), 1934 December- 1938 December (Box-folder 489 / 15)
    - Ledger, 1939 January- 1958 December (Volume 1226)
- Unidentified Records
  - Financial Records
    - Ledger, 1906-1910 (Box-folder 490 / 1)
    - Ledger indexes, undated (Box-folder 490 / 2-5)